PROFESSOR: OK.
One last important thing about how
these things work in practice--
is, in general, Q-Learning will only
take you so far, and what people often
do in practice to make these
really work is something
called policy search.
In policy search what you do is you
directly try to improve the policy.
And the problem with things
like Q-Learning is, what
does Q-Learning do?
It tries to figure out the
Q value of the state.
It's modeling the states.
But that may not be the same
setting of the weights
that makes good decisions.
So in particular, in project 2, you
wrote down 5 times the distance to the
dot minus 2 times the distance
to [? go ?] squared.
That was almost certainly not the actual
value of the state, but it
distinguished good states
from bad states.
And that's a general thing.
Q-Learning tries to get the
values close in general.
It does not try explicitly to make the
best action from a state have a higher
value than the worst action
from the state.
It doesn't try to order the Q values.
It just tries to get their
magnitudes right.
For action selection, you only
care about the ordering.
Now, of course, if the Q values were
close enough, their orders would be
correct as well.
But we're never perfect, and
so there's a trade-off
between these things.
We'll also see this in much greater
detail in the second half of the
course, that there's a trade-off between
modeling, getting the values
right, and prediction, getting
the ordering right and
making the correct decision.
The solution to this is to learn
policies that maximize your rewards,
and to do that directly in some way.
And to not try so hard to figure out
what the values that predict the
rewards are.
Just learn the policies.
So policy search, in general,
starts with an OK solution.
For example, you might do some
Q-Learning for a while, or if you've
got like a helicopter or something
that's expensive to replace, you might
get an initial policy based on domain
knowledge or simulation.
And then you fine tune by essentially
hill climbing on the feature weights.
And here, when you hill climb, you just
change the feature weights and
you see whether your rewards over time
are better as opposed to just a
one-step look ahead, and then
do a Q magnitude update.
So here's the simplest way you
could do policy search.
Start with an initial linear valued
function, or Q function, which is in
the ballpark.
Take each feature and nudge it up and
down and see if your policy is better
than it was before.
It's pretty direct.
You don't actually need
the Q update here.
There's some problems.
How do we tell if the policy got better
in response to our nudge?
Well, we've got to run a lot of episodes
because it might have only
gotten a little better, and it's going
to take a lot of samples to figure out
whether or not we're better or
worse, and that's going to
take a lot of trials.
If there are a lot of features, it's
going to be impractical to go to each
one, one by one, nudging it up
and down over and over again.
So, of course, better methods do exploit
the look-ahead structure like
Q-Learning.
They do sample wisely so you make the
best use of your experiences, and they
also change multiple parameters
at a time.
Here's an example of so you
can do with policy search.
This is an autonomous helicopter.
So this helicopter is flying itself.
But it's not actually that big.
You can't fit people in
these helicopters.
This is a model helicopter.
But it turns out helicopters
are very hard to fly.
Unlike a plane, which in many cases, if
you just more or less keep pushing,
you'll stay in the air for a while.
Helicopters are very unstable.
If you're not constantly correcting,
you don't stay in the
air for very long.
So it's hard to even get
a helicopter to hover.
It's not just about blast
air downward.
That actually does not work.
This is a way of getting helicopters
to hover that's trained and tuned
using policy search.
So here it is.
It's amazing.
You can get these things that hover on
their own, but it's actually even more
impressive than that.
Not only do they hover, they
hover upside down.
So not only can't you get people into
these helicopters, people don't want
to go into these helicopters.
We will see much more amazing things
with helicopters when we take a look
at some advanced topics later
on in the course.